<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>evolutionary public health on Academia</title>
    <link>https://examplesite.org/tags/evolutionary-public-health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in evolutionary public health on Academia</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://examplesite.org/tags/evolutionary-public-health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Premenstrual Syndrome &amp; Infection</title>
      <link>https://examplesite.org/post/pms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://examplesite.org/post/pms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;undiagnosed-stis-can-increase-negative-pms-symptoms&#34;&gt;Undiagnosed STIs can increase negative pms symptoms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;women-that-have-undiagnosed-sexually-transmitted-infections-may-be-at-greater-risk-of-experiencing-negative-premenstrual-symptoms-pms&#34;&gt;Women that have undiagnosed sexually transmitted infections may be at greater risk of experiencing negative premenstrual symptoms (PMS)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study was conducted as part of a long term partnership with the female health, fertility and period-tracking app, CLUE. The findings, &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.oup.com/emph/article/2018/1/138/5048464&#34;&gt;published in Evolution Medicine &amp;amp; Public Health&lt;/a&gt;, suggest that the presence of an undiagnosed STI might aggravate the negative premenstrual experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite being known to have an anti-social effect on women’s lives, altering their moods, energy levels, eating habits and even sex drive, periods are not recognised as a scientific factor in the study of female health. However, since some STI infections are asymptomatic, for instance 70% of people diagnosed with Chlamydia are unaware of it, and can lead to fertility issues, the study authors caution that these results are significant, and that reproductive health needs to be taken more seriously by both the scientific community and women in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ox.ac.uk/news/2018-09-17-undiagnosed-stis-can-increase-negative-pms-symptoms&#34;&gt;See the full press release here &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contraceptive Side-Effects</title>
      <link>https://examplesite.org/project/contraceptive-side-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://examplesite.org/project/contraceptive-side-effects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the developing world, millions of women discontinue hormonal contraception due to the experience of debilitating physiological side-effects (e.g. excessive and irregular bleeding), yet the causes of these adverse effects is not known. This project aims to test the hypothesis that side-effects are caused by unnecessarily high dosage of exogenous hormones in hormonal contraceptives compared with women’s endogenous hormones, with the aims of accumulating primary evidence for optimizing contraception to communities and individuals. The research focuses on the use of injectables in Ethiopia, where unmet needs for contraception reach the highest levels in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is in collaboration with &lt;strong&gt;Dr Eshetu Gurmu (co-PI)&lt;/strong&gt; from Addis Ababa University and &lt;strong&gt;Rose Stevens&lt;/strong&gt; (DPhil candidate, University of Oxford). See our first &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aau.edu.et/blog/workshop-holds-on-overcoming-contraceptive-discontinuation/&#34;&gt;workshop&lt;/a&gt; here. Due to COVID-19 restrictions, the project has been put on pause for the time being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our panel of &lt;strong&gt;expert advisors&lt;/strong&gt; for the project include Dr Sissay (Gynecologist, Ethiopia), Dr Tamrat (Microbiologist, Ethiopia), Dr Smith (LSHTM, UK), Dr Vitzthum (Indiana University, USA), Dr Sear (LSHTM, UK) and Dr Cresswell (WHO).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relevant publications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anaemic women are more at risk of injectable contraceptive discontinuation due to side-effects in Ethiopia
Rose Stevens, Blandine Malbos, Eshetu Gurmu, Jérémie Riou, Alexandra Alvergne
medRxiv 2020.10.28.20221523; doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1101/2020.10.28.20221523&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1101/2020.10.28.20221523&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alvergne, A., Stevens, R. &amp;amp; Gurmu, E. Side effects and the need for secrecy: characterising discontinuation of modern contraception and its causes in Ethiopia using mixed methods. Contracept Reprod Med 2, 24 (2017). &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1186/s40834-017-0052-7&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1186/s40834-017-0052-7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Menstrual Messages</title>
      <link>https://examplesite.org/project/menstrual_messages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://examplesite.org/project/menstrual_messages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Premenstrual changes in mood are usually reduced to and dismissed as women’s ‘raging hormones’. But what if a negative premenstrual experience is not a hormonal disorder but rather a message from the body about the socio-ecological causes of ill-health? Building on an established partnership with a technology company providing a period-tracker app with million of users, I am running a series of experiments to evaluate how the menstrual experience is shaped by social ecology, from the presence of pathogenic microorganisms to negative societal discourse about menstrual cycling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.thebritishacademy.ac.uk/funding/mid-career-fellowships/past-awards/2019/&#34; alt=&#34;Funded by the British Academy&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is in collaboration with &lt;img src=&#34;https://helloclue.com/&#34; alt=&#34;Clue&#34;&gt; and Gabriella Kountourides (DPhil candidate, University of Oxford)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relevant publications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alexandra Alvergne, Marija Vlajic Wheeler, Vedrana Högqvist Tabor, Do sexually transmitted infections exacerbate negative premenstrual symptoms? Insights from digital health, Evolution, Medicine, and Public Health, Volume 2018, Issue 1, 2018, Pages 138–150, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/emph/eoy018&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1093/emph/eoy018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Evolutionary Ecology of Menopause</title>
      <link>https://examplesite.org/project/menopause/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://examplesite.org/project/menopause/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;moving-on-from-why-menopause-evolve-to-understanding-diversity-in-age-at-menopause&#34;&gt;Moving on from why menopause evolve to understanding diversity in age at menopause&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project we aim to test the hypothesis that the determinants of age of natural menopause may be similar to the genetic, developmental and ecological determinants of ageing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is in collaboration with Abby Fraser (PhD candidate, University of Glasgow). If you want to know more about menopause have a look at Abby&amp;rsquo;s video below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://youtu.be/gnV1Yfop93s&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;{width=&amp;ldquo;560&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;315&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;** Relevant publication **
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ecoevorxiv.org/s59rh/&#34;&gt;https://ecoevorxiv.org/s59rh/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
