<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>periods on Academia</title>
    <link>https://examplesite.org/tags/periods/</link>
    <description>Recent content in periods on Academia</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://examplesite.org/tags/periods/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Menstrual Messages</title>
      <link>https://examplesite.org/project/menstrual_messages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://examplesite.org/project/menstrual_messages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Premenstrual changes in mood are usually reduced to and dismissed as women’s ‘raging hormones’. But what if a negative premenstrual experience is not a hormonal disorder but rather a message from the body about the socio-ecological causes of ill-health? Building on an established partnership with a technology company providing a period-tracker app with million of users, I am running a series of experiments to evaluate how the menstrual experience is shaped by social ecology, from the presence of pathogenic microorganisms to negative societal discourse about menstrual cycling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.thebritishacademy.ac.uk/funding/mid-career-fellowships/past-awards/2019/&#34; alt=&#34;Funded by the British Academy&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is in collaboration with &lt;img src=&#34;https://helloclue.com/&#34; alt=&#34;Clue&#34;&gt; and Gabriella Kountourides (DPhil candidate, University of Oxford)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relevant publications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alexandra Alvergne, Marija Vlajic Wheeler, Vedrana Högqvist Tabor, Do sexually transmitted infections exacerbate negative premenstrual symptoms? Insights from digital health, Evolution, Medicine, and Public Health, Volume 2018, Issue 1, 2018, Pages 138–150, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/emph/eoy018&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1093/emph/eoy018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Survey on Periods, Lock Down and COVID</title>
      <link>https://examplesite.org/post/covid-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://examplesite.org/post/covid-study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We need you!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://oxfordanthropology.eu.qualtrics.com/jfe/form/SV_8bHC9OHudZtahaB&#34;&gt;Check out our latest &lt;strong&gt;survey&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to help us understand better how the pandemic has influenced our menstrual cycles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you are currently menstruating, pregnant, breastfeeding, on contraceptives, HRT, or having menopause, no matter whether or not you&amp;rsquo;ve been infected with COVID, &lt;strong&gt;you can help&lt;/strong&gt;!!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are using a &lt;strong&gt;menstrual cycle app&lt;/strong&gt; and are willing to share your data for research purposes only - you can also contact me directly - I am looking for digital health data collected before and during the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you very much indeed!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
