<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Academia</title>
    <link>https://examplesite.org/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Academia</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://examplesite.org/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Collaborations</title>
      <link>https://examplesite.org/project/2020-11-16-collaborations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://examplesite.org/project/2020-11-16-collaborations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To be continued&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am currently contributing to two ongoing projects with fellow anthropologists&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-emergence-of-wealth-inequalities&#34;&gt;The emergence of wealth inequalities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See more details about the &lt;a href=&#34;https://endowproject.github.io/about-us/&#34;&gt;Endow Project&lt;/a&gt; led by Dr Jeremy Koster (cincinnati) and Dr Eleanor Power (LSE)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-social-dynamics-of-female-genital-mutilationcutting&#34;&gt;The social dynamics of female genital mutilation/cutting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See more details about the project  led by Dr Mhairi Gibson (Bristol University) and Dr Eshetu Gurmu (Addis Ababa University) &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thebritishacademy.ac.uk/projects/heritage-dignity-violence-social-dynamics-female-genital-mutilation-cutting/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contraceptive Side-Effects</title>
      <link>https://examplesite.org/project/contraceptive-side-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://examplesite.org/project/contraceptive-side-effects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the developing world, millions of women discontinue hormonal contraception due to the experience of debilitating physiological side-effects (e.g. excessive and irregular bleeding), yet the causes of these adverse effects is not known. This project aims to test the hypothesis that side-effects are caused by unnecessarily high dosage of exogenous hormones in hormonal contraceptives compared with women’s endogenous hormones, with the aims of accumulating primary evidence for optimizing contraception to communities and individuals. The research focuses on the use of injectables in Ethiopia, where unmet needs for contraception reach the highest levels in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is in collaboration with &lt;strong&gt;Dr Eshetu Gurmu (co-PI)&lt;/strong&gt; from Addis Ababa University and &lt;strong&gt;Rose Stevens&lt;/strong&gt; (DPhil candidate, University of Oxford). See our first &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aau.edu.et/blog/workshop-holds-on-overcoming-contraceptive-discontinuation/&#34;&gt;workshop&lt;/a&gt; here. Due to COVID-19 restrictions, the project has been put on pause for the time being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our panel of &lt;strong&gt;expert advisors&lt;/strong&gt; for the project include Dr Sissay (Gynecologist, Ethiopia), Dr Tamrat (Microbiologist, Ethiopia), Dr Smith (LSHTM, UK), Dr Vitzthum (Indiana University, USA), Dr Sear (LSHTM, UK) and Dr Cresswell (WHO).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relevant publications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anaemic women are more at risk of injectable contraceptive discontinuation due to side-effects in Ethiopia
Rose Stevens, Blandine Malbos, Eshetu Gurmu, Jérémie Riou, Alexandra Alvergne
medRxiv 2020.10.28.20221523; doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1101/2020.10.28.20221523&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1101/2020.10.28.20221523&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alvergne, A., Stevens, R. &amp;amp; Gurmu, E. Side effects and the need for secrecy: characterising discontinuation of modern contraception and its causes in Ethiopia using mixed methods. Contracept Reprod Med 2, 24 (2017). &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1186/s40834-017-0052-7&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1186/s40834-017-0052-7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family Ecology in a Matrilineal Society</title>
      <link>https://examplesite.org/project/family-ecology-matrilineal-society/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://examplesite.org/project/family-ecology-matrilineal-society/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Matrilineal systems differ from patrilineal systems most commonly found across the world in that descent and inheritance can be traced through the maternal line. This is not to say that men do not have an important political and social role. Tradiationnaly, in such systems, men  have an important role towards members of their clan, in particular the children of their sisters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Khasis are one such group living in Meghalaya, India, and are characterized by a huge diversity in living conditions (traditional, urban).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project aims to investigate how family ecology in matrilineal systems differ from what is usually observed in patrilineal systems, and its consequences for understanding diversity in female fertility and health. It is in collaboration with Dr Langstieh, Associate Professor of Anthropology in North Eastern Hills University (Meghalaya, India).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Menstrual Messages</title>
      <link>https://examplesite.org/project/menstrual_messages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://examplesite.org/project/menstrual_messages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Premenstrual changes in mood are usually reduced to and dismissed as women’s ‘raging hormones’. But what if a negative premenstrual experience is not a hormonal disorder but rather a message from the body about the socio-ecological causes of ill-health? Building on an established partnership with a technology company providing a period-tracker app with million of users, I am running a series of experiments to evaluate how the menstrual experience is shaped by social ecology, from the presence of pathogenic microorganisms to negative societal discourse about menstrual cycling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.thebritishacademy.ac.uk/funding/mid-career-fellowships/past-awards/2019/&#34; alt=&#34;Funded by the British Academy&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is in collaboration with &lt;img src=&#34;https://helloclue.com/&#34; alt=&#34;Clue&#34;&gt; and Gabriella Kountourides (DPhil candidate, University of Oxford)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relevant publications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alexandra Alvergne, Marija Vlajic Wheeler, Vedrana Högqvist Tabor, Do sexually transmitted infections exacerbate negative premenstrual symptoms? Insights from digital health, Evolution, Medicine, and Public Health, Volume 2018, Issue 1, 2018, Pages 138–150, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/emph/eoy018&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1093/emph/eoy018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Evolutionary Ecology of Menopause</title>
      <link>https://examplesite.org/project/menopause/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://examplesite.org/project/menopause/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;moving-on-from-why-menopause-evolve-to-understanding-diversity-in-age-at-menopause&#34;&gt;Moving on from why menopause evolve to understanding diversity in age at menopause&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project we aim to test the hypothesis that the determinants of age of natural menopause may be similar to the genetic, developmental and ecological determinants of ageing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is in collaboration with Abby Fraser (PhD candidate, University of Glasgow). If you want to know more about menopause have a look at Abby&amp;rsquo;s video below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://youtu.be/gnV1Yfop93s&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;{width=&amp;ldquo;560&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;315&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;** Relevant publication **
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ecoevorxiv.org/s59rh/&#34;&gt;https://ecoevorxiv.org/s59rh/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thyroid Health</title>
      <link>https://examplesite.org/project/thyroid-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://examplesite.org/project/thyroid-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We propose that dietary changes, ecological disruptions of co-evolutionary processes during pregnancy and with pathogens, emerging infections and exacerbated stress responses can contribute to explaining the onset of thyroid diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is project together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.boostthyroid.com/&#34;&gt;BOOST Thyroid&lt;/a&gt; and Sarai Keestra (Netherlands).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;** Relevant publication **
Sarai Keestra, Vedrana Högqvist Tabor, Alexandra Alvergne, Reinterpreting Patterns of Variation in Human Thyroid Function: An Evolutionary Perspective, Evolution, Medicine, and Public Health, , eoaa043, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/emph/eoaa043&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1093/emph/eoaa043&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
